SEAN NEDEN

SUMMARY

An experienced Software Engineer with a focus on Development for the web. I have experience in back end, front end and full stack roles. I have worked in companies from start-up to enterprise. I am a consistent, product focused engineer with an entrepreneurial spirit.

CONTACT

- sean.neden.name
- **6**02.703.0820
- **y** cannuk
- in seanneden
- Cannuk

EDUCATION

DeVry University Bachelors Computer Information Systems 2004

EMPLOYMENT

Curriculet Lead Engineer

Oct 2012 to Current

As Curriculet's first engineer, I have been involved in most of the Engineering related functions of the company. This includes (but is not limited to):

- Created the core of the Curriculet eBook reading experience, a fundamental piece of Curriculet's business.
- Architected, directed and helped create the front end of all of Curriculet's features.
- Authored and maintained policies around hiring, code reviews, testing and other engineering policies.
- Participated in 2 week customer support rotations with direct contact with customers via phone and email.

Pipewise

Senior Engineer

An innovative CRM built with Ruby on Rails, CoffeeScript and Backbone is. I worked as a full stack engineer with an emphasis on front end development.

GoDaddy.com

Senior Software Developer

- A developer on Website tonight (a WSIWYG website builder), I created an HTML5 (Canvas) Image editing solution which allows users to edit images within the browser. Edit functionality includes crop, re-size, rotate, color adjustments (hue, saturation), and contrast adjustment as well as adding and manipulating text. Image edits are shown in the browser in real time.
- Worked to move an existing and legacy Javascript code base to a modern modular design using Backbone and Require. Created documentation to help other developers transition to the new pattern.
- Coordinated deployments between Windows operations, and QA teams for a product with 900,000 users. Participated in on call activities, troubleshooting and resolving direct customer issues.
- Created internal developer tools to monitor data center network problems and automate previously manual processes.

Black, Gould & Associates

Senior Software Develope

Aug 2010 to Mar 2011

- Updated an existing web based Health Insurance rater product to focus on the user experience. Refactored from a traditional web form based solution to an entirely Javascript/ client side solution.
- Created an application wide theme editor which allowed users to change the look and feel of the application through a simple color picker and a real time view of the changes.

Oce Reprographic Technologies

Software Engineer

Feb 2004 to Aug 2010

- Technical Lead for a document distribution web application designed around the ASP.NET MVC framework, and the Dojo JavaScript Toolkit. Responsible for the majority of the design and architecture of the user interface and the C#/ ASP.NET backend
- · Lead Web Developer maintaining an existing project/document management web application with heavy use of JavaScript, AJAX, XML
- Creation of several advanced developer tools including a Database Mocking layer and Unit testing integration

Business Integration Group

Software Developer

May 2002 to Feb 2004

- Developed a web based Gantt chart allowing drag and drop editing of tasks using JavaScript and AJAX techniques.
- Developed and designed a complete document management solution allowing document sharing, uploading, versioning, etc. Solution was entirely web based and utilized extensive JavaScript.
- · Developed a customizable user portal to the Business Integration Group application, which allowed the user to create links and views to information they used the most.

SKILLS

JavaScript, Backbone.js, MySQL, AJAX, REST, Git, Ruby on Rails, User Experience, BDD, SQL, RSpec, CoffeeScript, Test Driven Development, MVC (Front and Back end)